Mr. Ao Oba?
你是大庭苍生先生？
Yes.
是
Could you come to the police station regarding the arson last night?
关于昨晚发生的纵火案 要请你跟我们去一趟局里
This is you, isn't it?
照片里这个人是你吧？
Is that you?
这个人是你吗？
I…
我…
I've no intention of switching firms.
没有想要换律所
Right.
哦
You'll be able to use your ability to the fullest over there.
到了那边 你的实力才能充分发挥
But I don't want--
就说了我不会去…
Yoshio!
佳男
Maybe not right now.
就算现在不想去
But you will.
以后还是会的
Here. Your favorite jelly from Kinpakuya.
来 这是你最爱吃的金箔屋的果冻
How long will he continue to see me as the child I was…
什么时候才不把我当小孩…
You know, today is a Saturday.
今天可是星期六
Mr. Oba's been arrested.
大庭先生被抓了
Huh?
什么？
He's in a detention center right now.
现在被关在拘留所里
Huh? What? Why?
什么？为什么？
It seems to be an arson case, but I don't know the details.
好像跟纵火案有关 具体情况我不清楚
I'm on my way now.
我立刻过去
SENOO POLICE STATION
（妹尾警察局）
Press this button when you're done.
结束了按铃通知我
You've been through a lot.
真是辛苦你了
So,
那么…
what happened?
发生了什么事？
How were you falsely arrested?
警方怎么会抓错人？
I did it.
是我做的
You mean you started the fire?
你说火是你放的？
Yes.
对
Why?
理由呢？
Why won't say anything?
你为何什么都不说？
I've…
我…
I've got nothing to say.
没什么好说的
Hey…
嘿…
What?
什么？
How was Mr. Oba?
大庭先生怎么样了？
He didn't do it, did he?
他没纵火吧？
He said he did.
他说是他做的
Then he kept his silence.
之后就一直保持沉默
I don't know what's going on.
不知道这是怎么回事
Please take a look at this.
请你看一下这个
In a park in Senoo City of Tokyo, a public toilet was set on fire
东京都妹尾市 一处公园的公共厕所遭人纵火
and an unidentified body was found in the remnants of the fire.
在灰烬中发现一具身份不明的尸体
Did you kill and burn the victim?
是你杀了被害人 然后纵火的吗？
The arrested suspect is
依纵火罪嫌遭到逮捕的是
a 26-year-old office worker who lives in Toda, Saitama.
住在埼玉县户田市的26岁上班族
According to the police, the security camera
根据警方表示 附近的摄像头
caught the suspect running away right after the fire started.
拍到嫌犯在火势起来之后 从现场逃走的样子
The police are also investigating him on suspicion of murder.
警方也在调查他杀人的嫌疑
Did Ao really say that he did it?
苍生真的说是他做的吗？
Yes. I'm going to see him again today.
对 今天我也会去见他
So, I'll keep you posted.
结果会再跟两位报告
Thank you very much.
麻烦你了
Excuse us.
那先这样
Ms. Ishida.
石田小姐
Ao told us that you two are dating.
我们听苍生说 你们在交往
Thank you for taking care of him.
我儿子受你照顾了
I'm sorry we had to meet this way.
居然是在这种情况下初次见面 真是不好意思
Please, don't be. He's been very good to me too.
不会 我才是受到他诸多照顾
Would Oba do this?
大庭会做这种事吗？
But he did say he did it.
但他都说是他做的了
Just to be sure…
确认一下
Mr. Oba really said "I did it," right?
大庭先生真的说“是我做的”吗？
Yeah.
对
If he just nodded to "Did you do it?" that's different. Do you get that?
如果只是点头响应“是你做的吗” 这是完全不同的状况 你知道吧？
What? He said, "I did it."
怎样？他的确说了“是我做的”
In what kind of nuance?
用什么语气说的？
Nuance?
语气？
Like, was he forced to say it? Or was he stressed--
是被逼的 不得不这么说…
What?
什么？
I'm sorry. I'm taking it out on you.
抱歉 我这只是在迁怒
We can't visit him because he's keeping his silence.
因为他保持沉默 所以我不能去见他
There's nothing I can do.
我什么事也不能做
Hey.
嘿
If only I wasn't a paralegal to begin with, right?
要是我不是律师助理就好了
If only I had the qualifications.
要是有律师资格就好了
Let's calm down first.
你先冷静一下吧
Okay?
好吗？
I know you're upset.
你很震惊吧
I'm really upset.
我也非常震惊
I want to believe he didn't do it too.
我也想要相信不是他做的
But if I act out of my feelings, you'll be like,
但是抱着想要相信他的心情行动 这是不行的吧？
it's against Lawyer Ethics.
违反律师伦理
Right?
对吧？
I'll go see him until he talks.
在他愿意开口之前
As many times as it takes.
我会一直去看他的
Okay.
好
The police are interrogating the arson suspect
警察持续审问 因涉嫌纵火而遭到逮捕的男子
and trying to identify the body…
同时也想要确认遗体的身份…
Here.
给你
REAL ESTATE INVESTMENT FRAUD CASE MR. YOSHIKI TAKAOKA
（不动产投资诈欺案件 高冈良树先生）
You seem to be having a hard time preparing for your case.
爸那边的案子 也准备了很长一段时间吧
It's a fraud case, so it's hard to collect evidence.
诈骗案很难搜集到证据
Well, I'll just do what I can.
也只能尽我所能去做
One step at a time.
从我能做的地方一步一步去做
Yes. Oh, hello.
喂 你好…
Yes, I'm sorry. Thank you.
是 不好意思 谢谢
About that case, right? Yes, thank you very much.
是那个案子吧？好 谢谢
Mr. Mikogami, my childhood friend is sad because she can't see her busy boyfriend.
御子神先生想请教你 我的青梅竹马 因男友太忙见不到面而难过
What should I say to her?
要怎么安慰她比较好？
MIKOGAMI'S CONSULTATION ROOM
（御子神的咨询室）
Let's see. She's sad because she can't see him.
的确 见不到面会很难过
But doesn't that also mean she was able to reaffirm her love for him?
但这不也代表 能再次确认对他的爱意吗？
Sorry for the sudden visit.
不好意思 我突然过来
I came up with something I could do as a paralegal.
我想到身为律师助理可以做些什么了
-Come in. -Oh, no.
-进来吧 -不
It's against my rules, so here's fine.
这样违反我的原则 在这里谈就好
Is it the time to be saying that?
都什么时候了还说那种话？
It's me. Nothing's gonna happen.
有我在 不会有事的
Do that outside.
在外面甩水
Thanks for having me.
谢谢你让我进来
You're currently in a situation where you can't meet Oba, right?
你现在见不到大庭吧？
Yes.
对
Maybe it was a good thing because you're able to reaffirm your love for him.
能因此再次确认对他的爱意 或许也算是好事一件吧
What?
什么？
Right, I'm sorry. I was wrong.
抱歉 我说错话了 对不起
So, what were you saying?
所以你要说什么？
Mr. Haneoka.
羽根冈律师
I need a favor from you.
我要请你帮个忙
SENOO POLICE STATION
（妹尾警察局）
There's no deciding factor to rule it as
还无法判断是案件还是意外
incident or accident, so police are looking into both.
警方似乎两方面都会进行调查
Did you kill someone?
你杀人了吗？
You won't talk, huh?
还是什么都不说吗？
This is a letter from Ishiko.
石子小姐写给你的信
"Mr. Oba, are you alright?"
“大庭先生 你还好吗？
"The fact that you're keeping your silence…"
你之所以保持沉默…
"…probably means you have a reason why you can't tell us so easily."
应该是有什么 无法轻易向我们吐露的苦衷吧
"But we've seen the kind of person you are through working with you
但是我们你一起工作 共同度过的这段时间
and through spending time together."
已经了解了你是怎样一个人
"We've seen you fight hard to save your friend at work."
想要帮助职场上的朋友 拼命奋斗的样子
"You tried to make us laugh when we were feeling down."
在我沮丧的时候 想要逗我笑的样子
"How you try to explain something but your feeling comes first
想要解释某件事 却因为情绪太过激动
and you can't explain it properly."
而无法好好解释的样子
"But because of that, it gets through to people."
但也因此让我们清楚感受到你的心意
"You're genuine, so you're honest about everything even if it could hurt you."
正直如你 连自己的缺点都会老实说出来
"When surprised…"
惊讶的时候
"…your reaction…"
‘这么夸张吗？’
"…is so big that it surprises us."
你的反应大到让我们吓一跳
"Because we know many qualities of yours,
就因为我们这么了解你
we think that you're keeping your silence for the right reason."
你一定有什么正当的理由 才无法对我们开口吧
"And we're very worried that you might be suffering
我们非常担心你是不是
because of that reason."
因此而痛苦万分
"Whatever reason you may have…"
不管你有什么苦衷
"…we want to help you."
我们都想要帮你的忙
"Mr. Oba,
大庭先生
please trust Mr. Haneoka and me."
也请你相信我和羽根冈律师
"We cannot help you unless you speak up."
如果你不主动发声 我们也帮不上忙
"It's my turn now to offer my umbrella to you."
这次轮到我为你撑伞了
"You helped me when I was soaking wet."
就像你曾经为被雨淋湿的我撑伞一样
"So, we will shelter you from the rain this time."
我们也想要为你挡住这场雨
"When everything is over and you're free…"
等到一切结束 你重获自由的时候
"…let's have a meal together again."
再一起吃饭吧”
I'm so sorry!
对不起
For not talking.
什么都没说
All this time, I didn't know what to do.
我一直不知道该如何是好
But…
但是…
can I trust you two and tell you everything?
我可以相信两位 把一切都告诉你们吗？
Of course.
当然
I…
我…
I wanted to protect my little brother.
我是想要保护弟弟
I'm home.
我回来了
That night, I happened to be back at my parent's place.
那天晚上 我刚好回老家一趟
Mom? Mom?
妈…
My brother took my jacket for his walk.
我弟穿了我的外套去散步
And he came back about an hour later.
大概一小时之后回到家
There was a loud noise at the door
在门口发出了很大的声音
and when I went to see, he looked scared and also injured.
我过去一看 他一副惊恐的样子 还受了伤
I knew something had happened.
我想应该是发生了什么事
But he was too terrified to talk.
但是他害怕到没办法讲话
The next day, when they told me I was caught on security camera,
第二天 听说摄像头拍到了我的样子
I remembered that my brother was wearing my jacket.
想起来我弟弟之前穿了我的外套
And you thought your brother had done it.
所以你觉得是你弟做的？
Yes.
对
I want to believe that he didn't do it.
我想相信不是我弟做的
But a part of me isn't sure and I'm really confused.
但又不知道到底发生了什么事 脑子一团乱
But…
但是
I cannot let them interrogate my brother.
我绝对不能让警方调查我弟
Sorry.
不好意思
I have siblings too, but why are you so protective of him?
我也有姊姊 但你为什么不惜这么做也要保护他
My brother, Taku…
我弟弟阿拓
He was born with an inability to interact with people.
生来就不擅长与人互动
He can't even go out during the day.
甚至在白天都不敢出门
That's why he takes walks late at night.
所以才会在晚上出门散步
He won't be able to go through an interrogation.
他一定没办法应付警方的审问
I'll remain to be the suspect.
我会继续当嫌疑犯
If I tell the police I didn't do it, Taku will be arrested.
要是我现在告诉警察不是我做的 阿拓就会被逮捕
So, could you and Ishiko prove that Taku is innocent
所以可以请羽男先生和石子学姐 代替我证明
on my behalf?
阿拓的清白吗？
No, wait. Hang on. That's impossible.
不 等一下 行不通的
I mean, you've already confessed.
因为你都已经自白了
Even if we did prove your brother's innocence,
就算我们真的能证明你弟是清白的
that doesn't mean we can overturn your confession.
也不一定能推翻你的自白
You could even get convicted. It's too risky.
你还是有可能会被定罪 这样太冒险了
I know that it's a huge risk.
我知道风险很大
But I have to protect Taku.
但我无论如何都想保护阿拓
You keep your silence.
你什么都别说
Don't answer anything they ask you.
无论如何都别开口
However this case develops, don't say a word.
就算今后案情有什么发展 也什么都别说
Then, at least, they won't look into your brother.
这样一来 至少警方就不会调查你弟
Meanwhile, we'll do whatever we can.
这段期间 我们会竭尽所能
So, hang tight until then.
所以你要撑下去
Okay.
好
But…
不过
I can't assume that your brother didn't do it without investigating.
我也不能未经任何调查 就认定不是你弟做的
So…
所以
we will investigate it from a fair point of view.
我会秉持中立的态度进行调查
Yes.
好
Also, when your detention period expires and they decide to prosecute you,
另外 等到拘留期满 检方决定要起诉你的时候
I will tell them that you didn't do it.
我会说出不是你做的
As a lawyer, I can't say you did when you didn't.
以我的立场 明明你没有做 我不能说是你做的
Is that alright?
这样可以吗？
We were hoping to talk to Taku about that day.
我们想跟阿拓谈谈那天的情况
Taku, you have guests.
阿拓 客人找你
They're Ao's friends.
他们是苍生的朋友
Hello.
你好
I heard you're a calligrapher.
听说你从事书道的工作
Yes.
对
Have you always been good at it?
你从以前就很会写书法吗？
I don't know.
不知道
These brushes are amazing.
这些毛笔好厉害啊
Are they all--
全部都是…
No! No, don't.
不可以
Sorry. I'm sorry.
对不起…
We'd like to ask you something.
我们有事情想问你
Four nights ago…
四天前的晚上
where were you and what were you doing?
阿拓 你当时在哪里 在做什么？
I heard you went for a walk.
听说你出门散步去了
I'm sorry. Please don't force yourself.
对不起 不要给自己太大压力
-I'm sorry.
-不好意思
AO
（苍）
What did you think?
你觉得呢？
I'm not sure yet.
还不知道
Whether it's arson or murder,
无论是纵火或杀人
he didn't seem like the type.
他看起来不像是会做那种事的人
We can't be sure yet.
我们还无法断定
Yes.
对
We need to get something out of him for Oba's sake.
为了大庭 必须从他那里问出点什么
Taku.
阿拓
He doesn't seem ready to talk yet.
好像还没办法说吧
You know…
你知道…
I never knew why I freeze up or why my hand trembles.
虽然不知道为什么 会身体僵住或手发抖
But I think it's my dad.
但我想大概是因为我爸吧
What?
什么？
Ever since I was a kid, he told me not to show my emotional swings to people.
从小他就会跟我说 不能让人看出内心的动摇
Emotional swings?
内心的动摇？
Yeah.
对
He said there are people who'll take advantage of you when you're agitated.
因为你情绪一激动 就会有人想要利用这个机会
I wonder if it has to do with his job.
是因为他工作的关系吧
And now that I've become a lawyer, there's nowhere to run in court, right?
不过现在我当上了律师 在法庭上就无处可躲了
I have to face the pressure no matter what.
无论如何 我都得面对压力
But you and your dad are the opposite.
不过所长和你却相反
When I'm agitated, you're right by my side trying to support me.
就算我情绪激动 你们还是会陪在我身边 想要帮我
The other day, when my hand trembled for the first time in a while,
但前几天 我的手又久违地抖了起来
I asked myself, "It hasn't happened in so long, so why now?"
我在想明明最近都没有发作了 到底是为什么呢？
Then I realized you weren't by my side,
原来那个时候你没有在我身边啊
Ishiko.
石子小姐
Why am I talking about this?
我为什么要说这个？
So, you see…
所以说…
What I'm trying to say is that
就因为你会像那样陪着他人
I think Taku will eventually open up to you
我想如果是你的话
because you're a compassionate person.
阿拓到后来也会愿意开口的
So, let's keep trying. Okay?
所以就一起加油吧？
You want some tea?
要喝茶吗？
Here.
给你
You're all a bunch of fools!
你们这帮笨蛋
Who got annoyed?
有谁觉得不爽吗？
That's a bad sign.
你们都很危险
I believe that not even one percent of your emotions are needed for business.
我认为在商场上 一丝一毫的情绪都没有必要
Anger, agitation, anxiety.
愤怒、动摇、不安
They're all a burden.
全都会成为负累
That's why losers lose many times.
所以失败的人才会一直失败
What clouds your judgment is emotion.
会造成误判的原因就是情绪
The Ministry of the Environment requested you to be their standing director.
环境省的人在问 能不能请你担任常务理事
Sure, anytime.
随时可以啊
There's a smoking area on the first floor too.
一楼也有吸烟区
If people saw me, it'll ruin my image.
让人看到了 有损我的形象
Eco-friendly and clean.
环保干净
I see.
原来如此
Excuse me.
先失陪了
A man found a large snake
在町田市中心的河床上
buried in a clay pipe at a riverbed in the center of Machida.
有一条大蛇被埋在陶管当中…
Oh, hey. Are you eating that with chopsticks?
嘿 你要用筷子吃吗？
The snake was six meters long…
那条大蛇足足有六米长…
I-I split them for you.
我…是帮你拆的
Thank you.
谢谢
-It's Shiozaki! -Huh?
-我是盐崎 -什么？
Hi there.
你们好
I'm here for the empty plates.
我来回收餐具了
I'm sorry. We've been busy so we're about to have lunch now.
抱歉 今天太忙了 我们现在才要吃午餐
Thank you for the food.
我要开动了
-Sorry. -Oh, right.
-不好意思 -这样啊
Then, can I eat here too?
那我也可以在这里吃吗？
-Man, it's so busy today. -Here.
-老天 今天忙死了 -给你
That's a good thing.
忙是好事啊
I'm thankful we got more regular customers,
常客增加了我是很感谢
but some of them talk endlessly and it's a hassle.
但有的客人话匣子一打开就停不下来 我也是很困扰的
Is he whining?
他在发牢骚吗？
Please hear me out.
请听我说
They're a married couple. Mr. and Mrs. Matsuda…
他们是一对姓松田的夫妻…
Now he is.
现在完全就是在发牢骚
Let's listen.
就听他说吧
…they said they pick up trash.
他们说会去捡垃圾…
They are talking to the office worker
警方持续向该名男性上班族问话
but he has remained silent for the alleged murder.
但是对于杀人嫌疑 他仍然保持沉默
The police have identified the body as Riichiro Hyuga.
警方也公布了遗体的身份 是住在埼玉县真锅市的
A taxi driver from Manabe, Saitama.
出租车司机 日向理一郎先生
Gasoline has been found on his body.
警方在日向先生的遗体上 检测出了汽油成分
-Police are looking into what happened. -Riichiro Hyuga.
-警方正进一步调查起火原因 -日向理一郎
The president of the taxi company where he worked at…
向先生任职的 出租车公司社长表示…
I'd like to meet his family and talk about the case.
我们想跟死者家属见面 询问案情
I'm not sure.
我不确定
I doubt she'd want to.
恐怕对方不想见面
In that case, as the prosecutor in charge, I can't let you see her.
那样的话 身为负责检察官 也没办法帮你们联络
But we may need to talk about compensation too.
不过我们可能也要讨论赔偿问题
Oh, I'm Haneoka.
我是羽根冈
Thank you for taking the time.
不好意思 初次见面
I'm Haneoka from Ushio Law Firm.
我是潮法律律所的羽根冈
I'm Aya Hyuga.
我是日向绫
I'm Ishida, the paralegal.
我是律师助理石田
I'm sorry, I couldn't quite get my lunch break on time.
不好意思 午休时间一直延后
No problem. Please have a seat.
不会 请坐
What would you like to drink?
您想喝点什么吗？
I can't just ask for water, can I?
不能喝水就好是吧？
It's pricey here.
这里很贵的
We asked you here, so it's on us.
是我们找您过来的 这里的费用当然算我们的
Then I'll have a coffee.
那就咖啡吧
-Excuse me, one coffee please. -Sure.
-不好意思 请给我们一杯咖啡 -好的
One moment please.
请稍等
Thank you very much for--
今天谢谢您…
I also want to know why my husband had to die.
我也想知道我先生为什么会死
The culprit.
凶手
What did he say?
有说什么吗？
About that…
关于这件事
The suspect hasn't spoken a word and we don't know if he's involved--
嫌犯什么也没说 也还不确定他有没有涉案…
Of course he's involved.
他当然涉案了
Oba killed my husband.
大庭杀了我先生
What makes you say that?
您有什么根据吗？
My husband was deceived by Green Estate.
我先生被绿色不动产骗了
We filed to cancel the contract but they won't pay us back
我们申请解约了 对方也不还钱
and the police told us it's not exactly fraud.
连警察也说这不算诈骗 把案子推掉了
I'm sorry, what is Green Estate?
不好意思 您说的绿色不动产是什么？
A real estate broker.
是一家房屋中介公司
Huh? What?
嗯？什么？
Have you not looked into this?
你们没有调查过吗？
We're terribly sorry.
非常抱歉
My husband and I were investing our retirement savings.
我和我先生为退休所存下来的钱 全部都拿去投资了
We even borrowed money for it.
不够的部分甚至还去借钱
That day, my husband went to see President Oba.
那天 我先生说要去找大庭社长
Excuse me, who do you mean by "President Oba"?
不好意思 您说的大庭社长是？
The president of Green Estate.
绿色不动产的社长啊
It's on the registration too. See?
就写在公司登记文件上
PRESIDENT, AO OBA
（社长 大庭苍生）
I’m sure he got killed over the refund.
我先生一定是因为要求退钱才被杀的
What is this? Did you know?
这是怎么回事 你知道吗？
Oh, yes.
知道
President Tone of Nakamaru, the company I originally joined,
我原先进去的那家中丸公司 那位刀根社长
was also the president of its subsidiary, Green Estate.
也是子公司绿色不动产的社长
-Right. -But President Tone…
-是 -不过刀根社长…
He said he wants me to run that company someday.
他说以后要把这家公司交给我
Huh? Why? So soon after you were hired?
为什么？就在你进公司之后？
Yes. I started working in September and he told me so in November.
对 我在九月入职 他在11月的晚宴上跟我说的
Because I'm the ace of his company.
他说“因为你是我们公司的精英”
And?
然后呢？
So, he said he'll register my name first as the president.
所以他说先把公司的社长 登记成我的名字
And you agreed to it?
你同意了吗？
Yes.
对
I was happy he had high hopes for me and I get an extra 100,000 per month--
他对我期待这么高 我很高兴 每个月还能领到十万的董事薪资…
You idiot!
你个白痴
You shouldn't fall for something so fishy.
这么可疑的事情怎么可以答应
What?
什么？
This Tone guy made you lend your name for some kind of scheme.
这个叫刀根的人是有其他目的 才会叫你把人头借给他
I was being deceived?
我被骗了吗？
Most likely.
很有可能
So, I was betrayed again.
我又被背叛了
We'll look into this too.
这方面我们也会去调查的
So, Mr. Hyuga saw the registration and went to see you, the president.
总之 过世的日向先生看了登记资料 才想去找你这位社长
But he mistook Taku for you because you two are similar in stature.
不过看到了身形跟你相似的阿拓 误以为是你 就上前跟他接触吗？
Taku hasn't said anything yet?
阿拓什么也没说吗？
No, not yet.
还没有
So it was my fault.
都是我害的
I thought I was protecting Taku,
我以为是在保护阿拓
but he got caught up in all this because…
但一开始他会被卷入就是因为我…
You said Taku was injured when he came home, right?
你说阿拓回家时有受伤吧？
Yes.
对
Mr. Hyuga tried to set Taku on fire out of resentment.
日向先生因为怀恨在心 想要对阿拓纵火
But Taku resisted and the fire spread to Mr. Hyuga himself.
但阿拓抵抗 火势反而烧到了日向先生自己
If this hypothesis is correct, Taku may have acted in self-defense.
如果这个假设成立的话 那阿拓算是正当防卫
SEVEN DAYS UNTIL THE DETENTION PERIOD EXPIRES
（距离拘留期满还剩七天）
Self-defense?
正当防卫？
-Yeah. -But we only have a week.
-对 -不过距离拘留期满只剩七天
I'll investigate if Mr. Hyuga prepared the gasoline himself.
我会去调查有没有 日向先生自己准备了汽油的线索
I'll continue on my side too, but the office is always empty.
我这边也会继续调查 但来了几次都没有人在
-Neighbors haven't seen anyone either. -I see.
-附近居民也没看到有任何人出入 -原来如此
GREEN ESTATE
（绿色不动产）
I'll stop by Mr. Oba's parent's house when I'm done here.
等这边结束之后 我也会去大庭先生家一趟
Yeah, thanks.
好 多谢
Ever since Ao was arrested,
苍生被捕之后
he's been writing the same character again and again.
那孩子一直在写同一个字
The first character of Ao's name.
一直在写苍生的“苍”字
I doubt he knows about the case,
他应该不知道案件的事情
but maybe he's feeling something.
但或许那个孩子已经察觉到什么了
They used to talk on the phone at least once a day.
毕竟他和苍生每天至少会通一次电话
Taku, there's something I really need to ask you.
阿拓 有件事情 我无论怎样都想要问你
Okay.
好
What happened with Mr. Hyuga that night?
那天晚上 你跟日向先生 有发生什么事吗？
Taku, answer her.
阿拓 快回答
Ao…
苍…
The character Ao has 13 strokes.
苍这个字有13个笔画
I'm sorry.
对不起
We are almost ready to sue, but we need something more solid.
提告的准备几乎已经就绪了 但就是缺乏更有力的证据
It's already been a year.
都已经一年了
Right.
是
Honestly, it's hard to make ends meet
说实话 我的生活有点困难
and I need the money.
很需要钱
Please get my money back now!
快点帮我把钱拿回来
Alright. Okay.
好…
I'll be off.
我先走了
REAL ESTATE INVESTMENT FRAUD CASE MR. YOSHIKI TAKAOKA
（不动产投资诈欺案件 高冈良树先生）
-Dad. -Hm?
-爸爸 -怎么啦？
Mr. Takaoka's case you've been working on. Tell me the details.
你一直在查的高冈先生这起案子 再跟我说说详情
Mr. Takaoka, a chiropractor,
高冈先生是脊椎按摩师
was approached by his customer, who works at Yotsuboshi Housing
有位客人是四星房屋的员工
about real estate investment.
推荐他去做不动产投资
And he was offered an apartment in Ishikawa.
介绍他一栋在石川县的公寓
The price was much lower than the market and he could be an owner.
价格比市场行情便宜很多 他买下来就能当房东
When he hesitated, he was told that
在他犹豫不决的时候 对方告诉他
he can expect immediate rental income as the rooms are already rented out
房间都已经租出去了 立刻就能收租金
and he won't make a loss.
绝对不会亏钱
So, he signed the contract.
对方这么说 他就签约了
That's right.
没错
But he didn't visit because it was already occupied and it was far.
不过因为房客都住满了 地点又很远 他没去看过房子
No, he didn't see it.
他没看过
Mr. Hyuga had also bought a property under the same circumstances.
被烧死的日向先生 也是在同样的情况下买进房子的
What?
什么？
Mr. Hyuga bought a 40-million-yen apartment in Toyama,
日向先生是以四千万日圆 买下位在富山的公寓
but it's pretty much the same.
但手法几乎一样
Here, the residents moved out one after another
他的状况是签约不到半年后
within six months of signing the contract and the rental income became zero.
原本的住户陆续搬走 房租收入完全归零
What?
怪了？
When he entered the empty room,
等到他进到空房间一看
the plumbing was in shambles and needed repair.
这才发现水管都已经损坏了 需要大幅修缮
Hmm, it's the same.
都一样啊
They consulted the police, but couldn't proof that it was fraud.
即使去找警察 也无法证明这是诈骗
Their methods are too similar.
手法实在太像了
Yeah, indeed it is.
真的很像
Maybe this fraud is being manualized.
这样的诈骗或许已经有操作手册了
Excuse me. Hi.
打扰一下 你好
Hello.
你好
The other day at the park…
前几天在那边的公园…
Did this man come to fill gasoline in his car?
这个人有来这里买汽油吗？
These are the videos.
车库里的监控视频在这里
Thank you.
谢谢
By the way, which is Mr. Hyuga's car?
顺便问一下 日向先生的车是哪一辆？
It's the one at the back.
停在后面那辆
Mr. Hyuga was draining gasoline from a truck.
日向先生从卡车的油箱里抽出了汽油
I believe he went to see Mr. Oba with it.
他应该就是带着这个去找大庭先生吧
If you know something, please tell us.
如果您知道些什么 请告诉我们
Actually, when Mr. Hyuga was in touch with the real estate broker last March,
其实去年三月 日向先生跟房产中介公司接触时
Mr. Oba wasn't working at Green Estate.
大庭先生并未在绿色不动产任职
What?
什么？
At that time, he was working at this used car dealership.
当时他还在这间二手车行工作
Meaning, he wasn't involved with Green Estate--
也就是说 他跟绿色不动产完全无关…
But I checked. He was the president.
可是我们查到了他是社长
When was that?
什么时候查到的？
Last December.
去年12月
Right after we felt we were conned.
我们一觉得被骗就去查了
Mr. Oba became the president last November. And in name only.
大庭先生成为社长是去年11月的事 而且只是顶了个名头
He's only an employee of a company in a different industry.
他只是另一个行业的公司小职员
We think he was used as a scapegoat for when things went wrong.
我们认为他是遭人利用了 当成出事时的代罪羔羊
You mean…
你是说…
my husband resented Mr. Oba for something he had nothing to do with
我先生怨恨毫无关系的大庭先生
and now he's being accused of murder?
还害他被怀疑犯下了杀人罪？
That's right.
没错
If you know something, could you please tell us?
如果您知道些什么 可以请您告诉我们吗？
The day after…
我先生
my husband went to see Mr. Oba…
出门去找大庭先生的隔天
I found this in the drawer.
我在抽屉里发现了这个
At first, it seems he was planning on killing him.
一开始 我先生打算要杀了他
But he knew if he committed murder, it would cause me trouble.
但要是犯下杀人罪 就会连累到我
So he killed himself for the insurance money.
所以他决定自杀 这样就能领保险金
"Aya, I'm going to set myself on fire in front of Oba and kill myself."
“绫 我要在大庭面前自焚
"If they think my suicide is due to a nervous breakdown,
只要被认定是因为精神崩溃而自杀
you'll get the insurance money."
就能领到保险金
"I'm sorry this is the only way I could think of."
对不起 这是我唯一能想到的办法
"Aya,
绫
you cannot tell this to anyone."
这件事绝对不能跟任何人说
"Aya."
绫…”
I WANT YOU TO LIVE ON WITH A SMILE ON YOUR FACE.
（你要带着笑容好好活下去）
I'm sorry I hid this from you.
对不起 一直瞒着你们
Don't be…
不会
Please have some tea.
请喝茶吧
I hoped that the bad guy,
我原本以为
who deceived us…
骗了我们的坏人
would be falsely charged with murder.
被误会成杀人犯再好不过了
I thought
我…
I'd kill him for my husband.
想要代替我先生杀了他
I can't believe I had the wrong person.
没想到竟然搞错人了
If you'd reveal all that,
只要你在法庭上说出这一切
Mr. Oba will be saved.
就能救大庭先生
I'll tell them everything.
我会把一切都说出来
I need to confirm this,
我确认一下
but the insurance money will no longer be paid.
这样就领不到保险金了
My husband was a very kind man.
我先生其实是很温柔的人
So, I don't think he'd want an innocent person
所以他一定也不希望
to be falsely charged.
害无辜的人被指控犯罪的
It's the same character, but each and every one is different.
即使是同一个字 每张写出来也都不一样
I like them all.
我全都喜欢
Got it.
知道了
PUBLIC PROSECUTOR'S OFFICE
（检察厅）
I'm sorry I didn't submit this.
很抱歉 我没有把这个交出来
It's okay.
没关系
We'll do a handwriting analysis to check if it's Mr. Hyuga's letter.
我们会送去做笔迹鉴定 看看是不是日向先生写的
-Oh, it is. -Even if it is.
-这是真迹 -就算是真迹
Unfortunately, a suicide note isn't enough to conclude this as a suicide.
很遗憾的 光凭遗书并不能断定就是自杀
I guess we'd need an eyewitness testimony.
还是要有目击者的证词啊
We only have one more day.
明天就拘留期满了
I'll go see Taku now and see if he's ready to talk.
我现在就去找阿拓 看能不能问出些什么
But if I can't get anything out of him, I'll tell them you didn't do it.
但如果还是问不出什么 我就会告诉你们不是你做的
I'm sorry. It's all my fault.
对不起 全都是我的错
All of it…
都是我…
Right. You should be sorry for lending your name without much thought
就是说啊 没想清楚就出借自己的名字
and for lying that you did it, even though you have your reasons.
即使有理由 但你谎称是自己犯案的 这两件事确实需要反省
But there's no need to feel remorse for anything else.
但除此之外 你没有什么好反省的
You're being a little too hard on yourself.
你有点太过自责了
And the one who should be blamed is not you nor Mr. Hyuga.
而且真正该受谴责的 不是你 也不是日向先生
It's those who deceive others.
而是诈骗的人
How's it going, Shoko?
怎么样了 硝子？
I'm still looking for a witness, but…
我还在找目击证人 可是…
I see.
这样啊
Something wrong?
怎么了吗？
No.
没事
We don't have enough evidence to prove that the deceased committed suicide.
要证明死者是自杀 还差临门一脚
Most importantly, Oba has admitted to the crime once.
更重要的是 他曾经一度认罪
I didn't think he did it for Taku.
没想到他竟然是为了阿拓
Did he think…
难道他以为
we'd be happy if he took the blame for Taku?
自己担下罪名 阿拓和我们会高兴吗？
Did Taku really do something?
阿拓真的做了什么吗？
We're not sure. That's why we'd like to speak to him.
这点我们也还不清楚 所以才想要跟他谈一谈
If it's ruled as arson murder, he'll receive a heavy sentence.
如果判定为纵火杀人 他就会被从重量刑
We need Taku to tell us what he knows.
我们希望阿拓能说出他知道的事情
Hello, Oba's residence.
你好 这里是大庭家
I'm with the Senoo police department.
这里是妹尾警察局
Mr. Sagane.
嵯峨根先生
I'm his mother.
我是他妈妈
Um…
他们是…
They're from a law firm.
律所的人
Oh, hello.
你们好
Um… Did he come here by himself?
请问 他是一个人过来的吗？
Yes, just suddenly.
对 突然就跑来了
He said he saw what happened at the park and he went quiet.
他只说看到公园发生的事 但之后就不讲话了
We weren't sure…
我们也搞不清楚…
If there's something he'd like to testify, please summarize it first.
如果是想要提供什么证词 请先整理之后再过来
Please wait a little longer.
请再等一下
My brother…
哥哥
was just trying to protect me.
只是想要保护我
That day, I…
我那天…
Hey, Oba!
喂 大庭
This is all your fault!
事情变成这样 都是你们害的
I'll never forgive you guys!
我永远不原谅你们
My life is ruined…
我的人生毁了…
Then are you the person who ran from the park?
这么说 从公园逃走的人是你吗？
Yes.
对
You mean, Mr. Hyuga set himself on fire after he verbally abused you?
日向先生骂了你之后就点火自焚吗？
Tell us.
是怎么样？
Taku. Taku, look at my eyes.
阿拓…看着妈妈的眼睛
Well, that testimony seems plausible given the circumstantial evidence.
刚刚的证词对照情况证据 好像没有不合理的地方
Of course, we must verify--
当然 我们也会去确认…
There was someone else.
还有一个人在
Someone was at the park.
还有人在公园里
Who else was there?
还有其他人在场吗？
He lit the fire.
是那个人点的火
Who did?
是谁点火的？
-Tell us! -I don't know. I…
-请告诉我们 -不知道…
Please stop.
不要再问下去了
Let's calm down.
先冷静一下
DETENTION EXPIRATION DAY
（拘留期满当日）
We must reprimand Mr. Ao Oba for perjuring himself,
大庭苍生供称是自己犯案 做伪证这件事还是需要究责
but after examining Mr. Taku Oba's testimony,
不过在确认过大庭拓先生的证词后
we've decided not to prosecute him.
检方决定不起诉处分
Thank you very much.
谢谢您
Ishiko.
学姐
Oh.
啊
Huh?
嗯？
Thank goodness!
太好了
I'm so glad!
真是太好了
Uh, um…
那个…
Welcome back!
欢迎回来…
Excuse me.
不好意思
-Hello? -What? Don't ruin our moment.
-先给我等一下 -怎么了？不要吵了
Yeah, my moment.
那是我的
Excuse me?
什么？
It's my moment. You did all of it.
我的台词和拥抱全部被你抢走了
You're not making sense.
听不懂你在说什么
He came towards me for a hug.
大庭张开手臂朝着我跑过来啊
It was for me. How could you not tell?
他是想要抱我 一看就知道吧？
It wasn't. I wanted to hug him anyway.
才不是 而且我也想要拥抱啊
I wanted to say "Welcome back" to him too.
我也想要跟他说“欢迎回来”啊
Say it now then! Go on!
那就现在说啊 快说
It's not the right timing anymore!
现在才叫我说 时机已经过了吧
What? Are you being shy?
在说什么 你害羞了吗？
Thank you very much!
谢谢你们
Thanks to you both,
多亏了两位
my brother and I didn't have to get arrested.
我和我弟弟都没有被逮捕
And I'm sorry.
还有 对不起
About lying and for making you worry.
我说了谎 还让你们担心了
We were very worried.
真的很担心
I'm sorry.
对不起
But Taku did his best.
不过阿拓很努力
Let's break this hug.
先分开来吧
Let us go, okay?
先分开来吧？
Oh, I'm sorry.
不好意思
And, Taku?
阿拓呢？
He testified everything he saw while taking breaks in between.
他视情况边休息边作证 把看到的事情都说出来了
AO
（苍）
In the end,
说到底
those who are deceived will continue to be deceived.
被骗的人就是会一直被骗
Those without power can't obtain information.
没有力量的人就得不到情报
They have no knowledge, so they continue to lose.
不知道情报 就会继续输下去
We're investigating the other person,
我们正在调查在场的另一个人
but we have nothing useful yet.
目前尚未得到有力情报
I won't let this slide!
我不会就此罢休的
I'll sue you, asshole.
小心我告你 混蛋
How about suing them together?
要不要联合提告呢？
It's not designed for the weak people to win.
弱势的人注定赢不了
Please help us.
请帮帮我们
Let's show them what the local lawyers are made of.
让他们看看本地的律师有多难对付
Subtitle translation by: Aya Kudo
字幕翻译：赤焰